A Guide to the 8th Evacuation Hospital 1941-2011
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Scrapbook of John Guerrant ND, Artifact: scrapbook includes photos and postcards (Box-folder 32-001)
  Included are photos of John Guerrant, the 8th Evac labs, Jefferson Day celebration, views of the 8th Evac camps, hanging of Mussolini, and postcards of Casablanca, Napoli, Rome, and Capri
- Photo album of William H. Laird ND, Artifact: scrapbook includes photos (Box-folder 32-002)
  Included are photos of 8th Evac sites and people.
- Addresses of Deceased 1946, notebook (Box-folder 33-001)
  The notebook contains the names of deceased soldiers and includes rank, injury, address for next of kin, date of death, and date of Beery's letter to next kin. After the war Beery wrote letters to the next of kin of those who died in the 8th Evac Hospital or who were dead on arrival.
- Letters from Ruth Beery 1946 February, 4 unopened envelopes with enclosed letters (Box-folder 33-002)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 10, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-003)
  Transcription of letter is available.
- Letter from Ruth Beery to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 17, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-004)
- Letter from Ruth Beery to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 17, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-005)
- Letter from Ruth Beery to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 18, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-006)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 19, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-007)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 20, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 newspaper clipping 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-008)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 21, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-009)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 22, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-010)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 22, 1 TLS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-011)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 23, 1 ALS 4 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-012)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 24, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-013)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 25, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-014)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 25, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-015)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 25, 1 ALS 4 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-016)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 25, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pg. (Box-folder 33-017)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 25, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-018)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 25, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-019)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 25, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-020)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 26, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-021)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 26, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-022)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 28, 1 ALS, 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-023)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 February 29, 1 ALS 2 pp., envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-024)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 1, 1 ALS 4 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-025)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 3, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, 1 newspaper clipping 1 pg., transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-026)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 3, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-027)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 4, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-028)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 6, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-029)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 7, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-030)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 8, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-031)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 9, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-032)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 10, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-033)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 10, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-034)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 10, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-035)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 11, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-036)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 12, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-037)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 12, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-038)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 18, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-039)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 18, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-040)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 21, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-041)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 23, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-042)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 23, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-043)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 26, 1 ALS 3 pp., transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-044)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 March 31, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-045)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 April 6, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-046)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 April 6, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-047)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 April 7, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-048)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 April 9, 1 ANS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-049)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 April 16, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-050)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 April 23, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-051)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 April 30, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-052)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 May 7, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 33-053)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 May 10, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-054)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 May 14, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-055)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1946 May 17, 1 ATL 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-056)
- Card to Ruth Beery 1946 December 23, 1 Christmas card, 1 envelope (Box-folder 33-057)
- Letter to Ruth Beery 1947 March 20, 1 ALS 3 pp., 1 envelope (Box-folder 33-058)
- Card to Ruth Beery 1947 December, 1 card 1 pg., 1 envelope (Box-folder 33-059)
- Letter to Ruth Beery in response to Beery's letter to next of kin of deceased soldier 1948 February 13, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 TL 1 pg (Box-folder 33-060)
- Letter to Ruth Beery 1948 February 23, 1 ALS 1 pg., 1 envelope, transcription: 1 Tl 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-061)
- Envelope from Ruth Beery ND, 1 envelope (Box-folder 33-062)
- Note by John Guerrant in regard to letters to Ruth Beery 1984 November 15, 1 ALS 1 pg. (Box-folder 33-063)
  Guerrant writes that after the war Beery wrote to the families of those who died at the 8th Evac Hospital. Beery saved the letters she received in response.
- Soldier's individual pay record for Frank Lowther 1943 April 30, 1 pamphlet with AN 12 pp. (Box-folder 34-001)
- "Going back to Civilian Life" by the War and Navy Departments 1945 August, 1 pamphlet 89 pp. (Box-folder 34-002)
- Basic Field Manual: Soldier's Handbook 1941 July 23, 1 book 251 pp. (Box-folder 34-003)
  contains chapters on general information; military discipline and courtesy; insignia; organization; clothing; arms and equipment; school of the soldier with and without arms; squad and platoon drill; interior guard duty; marches, camps, and bivouacs; use of compasses and maps; security and protection; military sanitation and first aid; the ration; pay and allowances; and the last will and testament
- "Rigoletta" by the San Carlo Opera Company ND, 1 program 4 pp. (Box-folder 34-004)
- Arm band with flag 1944, Artifact: white oil cloth imprinted with red and blue U. S. flag, 4" x 16.5" (Box-folder 34-005)
  This arm band was used by U. S. Air Borne Paratroopers
- V-Mail (Victory-mail) letter sheets ND, 6 TD (Box-folder 34-006)
  Letters written on these specially designed letter sheets were microfilmed. The microfilmed copies were sent instead of the letters and then "blown up" at an overseas destination before being delivered to military personnel, thereby saving valuable cargo space.
- Note good for one hour of condolence from Chaplain William H. Laird ND, 1 TN 1 pg. (Box-folder 34-007)
- V mail sent to Frank Lowther March 9, 1944 July 14, 1944 August 24, 3 facsimiles, 1 envelope, 4 pp. (Box-folder 34-008)
  These are facsimiles of the reduced-in-size V mail letter sheets.
- "The Stars and Stripes - Mediterranean" Vol. 2, No. 69 1945 August 30, 1 newspaper 8 pp. (Box-folder 34-009)
- Allied Military currency issue in Italy, 1, 2, 5, 10 and 50 lire 1943, 8 pieces of paper money (Box-folder 34-010)
- Certificate of Identity for Frank L. Lowther 1945 May 11, 1 card enclosed in plastic (Box-folder 34-011)
- War Department identification cards for Frank Lowther 1942 September 19, 1943 June 19, 2 cards with AN (Box-folder 34-012)
  Cards include fingerprints and photo.
- Fifth Army Rest Camp meal ticket and pass 1945 March 2, 1 card, punched (Box-folder 34-013)
- Troop Assignment Card ND, 1 card, punched (Box-folder 34-014)
  This card was used as a meal ticket throughout the soldier's voyage.
- New Testament given to Frank L. Lowther 1941 January 25, 1 book (Box-folder 34-015)
- Immunization register for Frank L. Lowther 1945 February 18, 1 TD with AN (Box-folder 34-016)
- Dogtags for Frank L. Lowther ND, Artifacts: 2 metal tags and chain (Box-folder 34-017)
- Letter from Alice Huffman Bugel to Joan Klein 2006 September 22, 1 ALS photocopy (Box-folder 34-018)
- Statue ND, 1 B&W 3.5 x 5 photo (Box-folder 34-019)
- Hospital plans ND, 2 TD mimeographed with AN, 5pp. (Box-folder 34-020)
  Includes a list of special equipment for medical and surgical wards, plan for bed ward, and a guide to the hospital plan.
- Mud, Mules, and Mountains: Cartoons of the A.E.F. in Italy by bill Mauldin 1944, 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 34-021)
- Road to Rome: Salerno, Naples, Volturno, Cassino, Anzio, Rome post 1944 June, 1 pamphlet, 56pp. (Box-folder 34-022)
- Eighth Evacuator 1950 December, mimeographed newsletter (missing page 1), 9pp. (Box-folder 34-023)
  Includes letters from Mark Clark and Joseph Martin, a special feature by Bill Laird on the presentation to UVa of the portrait of Dr. Staige Davis Blackford, and names and addresses.
- Bulletin of the University of Virginia Medical School and Hospital 1946 Spring, 1 journal, 34 pp. (Box-folder 34-024)
  Suspended for three years, this issue of the Bulletin gives priority to the military service of alumni and faculty, including a record of the 8th Evac.
- Halloran General Hospital, staten Island, NY, Christmas dinner 1942 December 25, 1 pamphlet, 12pp. (Box-folder 34-025)
  Includes the dinner menu and a list of personnel.
- C'est le Garre: Reminiscenses of a World War II Army Nurse by Elizabeth Engleman Carter 1990s, TD mimeographed 54pp. (Box-folder 34-026)
- The Marietta Daily Journal "MASH/TV show is 'True to Life,' World War II Nurse Says post 1972, 1 newspaper clipping photocopy (Box-folder 34-027)
  The article describes Langhorne Cloyd Iseman's experience with the 8th Evac.
- University of Virginia Alumni News: 8th Evac 1963 April, 1 journal 32pp. (Box-folder 34-028)
- Special orders, general orders for Thelma Matthews 1942-1965, 3 TD mimeographed 6pp., 11 TDs mimeographed 15 pp.,4 TDs 4pp., 1 TD with AN 2pp. (Box-folder 34-029)
- Thelma Matthews with unidentifed soldiers [1943-1945], PHOTOS 2-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 34-030)
- Thelma Matthews with 3 unidentifed women N.D., PHOTO 1 color 8 x 10 (Box-folder 34-031)
- Thelma Matthews (front center) with 5 unidentifed women [1985?], PHOTO 1 color 3.5 x 4.25 (Box-folder 34-032)
  The unidentified women are probably all 8th Evac nurses as the notation on the back states "6 of the 8 Frankie [Hilda Franklin?] and Huffie [Alice Huffman?] missing." The women appear to be the same as in Box 34, Folder 33.
- Thelma Matthews (front center) with 5 unidentifed women 1985, PHOTO 1 color 8 x 10 (Box-folder 34-033)
  The unidentified women are probably all 8th Evac nurses. The women appear to be the same as in Box 34, Folder 32.
- Thelma Matthews N.D., PHOTOS 1-B&W 8 x 10 and 1-B&W 7 x 10.25 (Box-folder 34-034)
- Thelma Matthews with patients N.D., PHOTOS 3-B&W 8 x 10 and 2 color 8 x 10 (Box-folder 34-035)
- Cartographs by Ruth Taylor White N.D., 4 color maps 9.25 x 12.25 (Box-folder 34-036)
  The maps are Island of Hawaii, Island of Kauai, Island of Oahu, and Island of Maui and were issued by the Hawaii Tourist Bureau. Matthews was stationed at Tripler in Honolulu.
- "Native Italians Say Zero Weather Soon Will Hit Front Lines" and "Miss Brubaker Weds E. W. Shearburn at University Chapel" N.D., 2 newspaper clippings (Box-folder 34-037)
- "The Stars and Stripes Mediterranean" vol. 1, no. 46 1944 August 1, 1 newspaper 8 pp. (Box-folder 34-038)
- Commendations, certificates and appointments of Thelma Matthews 1944-1952, 4 commendations, 2 certificates, 3 appointments (Box-folder 34-039)
- "The Draw Sheet" vol. 34, no. 9, "UVa's MASH unit recalls WWII" 1985 September, 1 newsletter 4pp. (Box-folder 34-040)
- "Service Stripe" Walter Reed Army Medical Center vol. 17, no. 7, "Who's News: Major Matthews" 1961 February 17, 1 newsletter 4 pp. (Box-folder 34-041)
- Letter from Joe Brusati to Joan Klein 2004 March 16, 1 letter 2 pp., 1 envelope, 3 photos (Box-folder 34-042)
  Brusati encloses 3 photographs: one of his sister Angela Brusati who was with the 8th Evac and two of her classmates. They called themselves with one other nurse, "The California Commandos."
- V-Mail from Prentice Kinser to Mrs. P. Kinser, Mrs. Gladys Kinser and Miss Patsy Kinser and Sonny 1938, n.d., 4 V-mail Christmas cards, 2 Christmas cards, 1 postcard (Box-folder 35-001)
  The letters from Prentice Kinser to his wife and other members of his family were stored in a small suitcase. This suitcase is now in Historical Collections' artifact collection. It is artifacts01230.
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser July 1942, 9 ALS, 9 envelopes (Box-folder 35-002)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and from Gladys Kinser to Mrs. L.R. Whitten August 1942, 1 ALS, 1 envelope, 1 postcard (Box-folder 35-003)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Jimmy September 1942, 2 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-004)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Pat and to Sonny October 1942, 5 ALS, 3 envelopes (Box-folder 35-005)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser November 1942, 1 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-006)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Pat and to Sonny and to Sugg December 1942, 1 ALS, 4 envelopes, 4 Christmas cards (Box-folder 35-007)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser January 1943, 4 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-008)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser February 1943, 3 ALS, 3 envelopes (Box-folder 35-009)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser May 1943, 2 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-010)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Patsy June 1943, 23 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-011)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser July 1943, 11 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-012)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser July 1943, 1 V-mail letter (Box-folder 35-013)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser August 1943, 14 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-014)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser September 1943, 10 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-015)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Patsy October 1943, 14 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-016)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser October 1943, 1 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-017)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser November 1943, 9 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-018)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and Patty November 1943, 2 ALS, 2 envelopes, 1 Christmas postcard (Box-folder 35-019)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Sonny and Patsy and Frances Morrow December 1943, 13 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-020)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser December 1943, 6 ALS, 5 envelopes (Box-folder 35-021)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser January 1944, 16 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-022)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Patricia February 1944, 14 V-mail letters, 2 V-mail valentines (Box-folder 35-023)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser February 1944, 9 ALS, 7 envelopes (Box-folder 35-024)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Prentice III and Patricia March 1944, 7 V-mail letters and 2 V-mail Easter cards (Box-folder 35-025)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser March 1944, 5 ALS, 1 V-mail letter, 6 envelopes (Box-folder 35-026)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser April 1944, 16 V-mail letters, 10 V-mail cartoons, 2 V-mail Mother's Day cards (Box-folder 35-027)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Patty May 1944, 11 V-mail letters, 13 V-mail cartoons (Box-folder 35-028)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser May 1944, 4 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-029)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and to Patty June 1944, 8 V-mail letters, 13 V-mail cartoons (Box-folder 35-030)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser June 1944, 1 ALS, 3 V-mail (original) cartoons, 2 envelopes, 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 35-031)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser July 1944, 8 V-mail cartoons, 3 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-032)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser July 1944, 3 ALS (Box-folder 35-033)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser August 1944, 5 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-034)
- Correspondence to Gladys Kinser and Patsy August 1944, 8 ALS, 9 envelopes, 2 newspaper clippings (Box-folder 35-035)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser September 1944, 4 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-036)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser September 1944, 1 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-037)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser October 1944, 2 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-038)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser October 1944, 1 ALS, 2 envelopes, 1 Christmas card (Box-folder 35-039)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser November 1944, 6 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-040)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and Sonny December 1944, 5 V-mail letters, 3 V-mail Christmas cartoons (Box-folder 35-041)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser and T.M. Whitten to Gladys Kinser December 1944, 7 ALS, 7 envelopes (Box-folder 35-042)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser January 1945, 3 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-043)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser January 1945, 1 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-044)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser February 1945, 3 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-045)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Patricia Kinser February 1945, 1 V-mail (original) Valentine (Box-folder 35-046)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser March 1945, 4 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-047)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and from T.M. Whitten to Gladys Kinser and Mother and Dad March 1945, 3 ALS, 2 envelopes (Box-folder 35-048)